<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>markbrown.io</title><link href="http://markbrown.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://markbrown.io/feeds/research.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://markbrown.io/</id><updated>2013-01-27T00:00:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>From Draft to Submission : Using Authorea</title><link href="http://markbrown.io/from-draft-to-submission-using-authorea.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-01-27T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Mark</name></author><id>tag:markbrown.io,2013-01-27:from-draft-to-submission-using-authorea.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve been using LaTeX for a while now but as anyone who uses the tool knows,
it can be painful at times. Large documents can quickly become unamenable to editing
and addition. The fact that most people learn informally as a de-facto method of improving
their &amp;#8216;presentation&amp;#8217; score on whatever respective undergraduate assignment given to
them does not&amp;nbsp;help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From that however the equation formatting, the ease of being able to edit figures
independently of LaTeX and frankly the ability to (cross-)reference effortlessly
has made be thankful daily for learning to use the tool&amp;nbsp;compentently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However in the time spent during my PhD, I&amp;#8217;ve come to rather dislike communal editing.
The dozens of paper versions impossibly attempting to recombine in a sane manner is quite
frankly a ridiculous time sink. Even worse, how many people actually perform version
control upon their own LaTeX&amp;nbsp;documents?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s with this in mind, in December I began writing a paper on experiment results
I&amp;#8217;d been able to collect with the kind assistance of the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PH&lt;/span&gt;-&lt;span class="caps"&gt;CMX&lt;/span&gt; group at &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CERN&lt;/span&gt;. Given
the dozen or so individuals involved with the work and given my fear of the above, I
decided to give authorea a&amp;nbsp;shot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tool breaks a research paper into cells, each containing text, equations, graphs
or tables. Anything we need, anything we could show in a paper. All text cells are included
in the root directory. Figures in recursively named directories in the &lt;a href="#id1"&gt;&lt;span class="problematic" id="id2"&gt;`&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;figure&amp;#8217; directory. Everything is cellotaped together to produce the paper in web version you can see. Exporting to different journal formats is certainly a useful first step, however I&amp;#8217;ve yet to find a single format that didn&amp;#8217;t need a subsequent bit of hammering. No doubt something that will be fixed in the months and years to&amp;nbsp;come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="system-message" id="id1"&gt;
&lt;p class="system-message-title"&gt;System Message: &lt;span class="caps"&gt;WARNING&lt;/span&gt;/2 (&lt;tt class="docutils"&gt;/home/mark/Desktop/Dropbox/markbrown.io/content/research/authorea.rst&lt;/tt&gt;, line 27); &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="#id2"&gt;backlink&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
Inline interpreted text or phrase reference start-string without end-string.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main thing that has made this tool invaluable to myself is the ability to edit the paper
from the raw information contained in a git repository. Replacing figures or updating tables can be as simple as copying and pasting the required information. There&amp;#8217;s also the side that we can leverage existing tools to get the job done much more efficiently. Why type out a large table and calculate errors by hand when we can do so by a combination of Python packages? Why waste time changing the font size of every single graph, individually when we can use rc parameters in an ipython notebook to accomplish the job at a single&amp;nbsp;stroke.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether these benefits add up in time I&amp;#8217;m not so sure. Many academics prefer (perhaps rightly) to read research articles on paper - An outcome authorea is currently difficult to convince into. Many more academics are uncomfortable with the technical side of editting a document in this fashion. For my part I believe part of moving away from the research journal market we&amp;#8217;ve allowed to arise, is to make academic publishing as easy as writing a blog&amp;nbsp;post.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>